Now that we have some tests,
现在我们有了这些测试
we can actually start testing to see how much gas each one of our functions actually costs.
就可以开始测试一下每个函数实际要花费多少 Gas 了
One of the most popular extensions for hard hat is the hard hat gas reporter.
Hardhat 最受欢迎的扩展之一是 "hardhat-gas-reporter"
This is an extension that gets attached to all of our tests,
这是一个可以附加在我们所有测试上的扩展
and automatically gives us an output that looks like this,
并自动提供类似这样的输出
that tells us approximately how much gas each one of our functions cost.
以告诉我们每个函数大约消耗了多少 Gas
We scroll down in here, we can read the instructions on how to actually install this
如果我们向下滑动到这里，可以阅读到有关如何安装这个扩展的说明
npm install Hardhead gas reporter
"npm install hardhat-gas-reporter"
which we're going to use with yarn.
但我们会使用 yarn 来安装
So we're gonna say yarn, add hard hat, gas reporter, dash dash Dev.
所以我们运行 "yarn add hardhat-gas-reporter --dev"
And now that that package is installed,
现在这个包已经安装好了
we can go over to our config and add some parameters in here
我们可以转到 "config" 文件中并在这里添加一些参数
so that we can work with this gas pit.
这样我们就可以使用这个 gas reporter 了
But our neath our ether scan section,
就在我们的 "etherscan" 部分下面
we're going to add a new section called gas reporter.
我们要添加一个新的部分名为 "gasReporter"
To have it run, whenever we run our tests
为了让它能在我们运行测试时运行
we're going to do enabled is going to be true.
我们要写下 "enabled" 为 true
And then up at the top, we can add it by adding require hardhat gas reporter.
然后在顶部，我们可以通过添加 "require("hardhat-gas-reporter")" 来添加它
Now that we have it in here, we can do yarn hardhat test,
现在我们已经有了这个包，就可以运行 "yarn hardhat test" 了
and after we run our tests, it'll automatically run this gas reporter.
并且在运行完测试之后，它会自动运行这个 "gas reporter"
So we see our tests go ahead and run.
现在我们看到我们的测试运行好了
And then we get this output that looks like this that tells us
并且我们获得了这样的输出，它告诉我们
how approximately how much our contracts and methods cost.
我们的合约和方法大约消耗了多少 gas
So our store function looks like It costs approximately this much gas
所以我们的 "store" 函数看起来大约需要这么多 gas
and our simple storage costs approximately this much gas.
以及我们的 "SimpleStorage" 大约需要这么多 gas
This is incredibly helpful for figuring out
这对我们来说很有用
how to optimize our gas as best as possible.
可以帮助我们最大程度地优化 gas 分配
Now I usually like to take it a step further though.
通常来说我喜欢更进一步
Having the gas output it like that is nice, but we can make it even better.
像这样输出 gas 消耗也不错，但我们能做得更好
I like to output it to a file by doing output file. Yes, report dot txt
我喜欢设置一个 "outputFile: gas-report.txt" 来把它输出成一个文件
and then my dot get ignore like to add it in here, but doing gas report dot txt
然后在我的 ".gitignore" 中把它添加进来 "gas-report.txt"
sentence it's not really important for the gas report to get pushed up to GitHub.
因为 gas 报告并不是那么重要的东西，没必要传到 github 上
Do no colors is true. The reason we add this is because when we output to a file,
设置 "noColors" 为 true，之所以这样设置是因为当我们输出到文件时
the colors can get messed up basically.
颜色基本上会比较混乱
And then the biggest addition we could do is we can add a currency in here.
接下来最大的改动是在这里添加一个 "currency"(货币)
So that we can get the cost of each function in USD for a blockchain like Aetherium.
这样，我们就可以获得在类似以太坊这样的区块链上每个函数的 USD 成本
Now in order to get a currency here,
现在，为了在这里获得 "currency"
we actually need to get an API key from corn market cap,
我们需要从 CoinMarketCap 上获取一个 API 密钥
just like we did with ether scan, you can go to coin market cap,
就像我们之前使用 etherscan 那样，你需要前往 CoinMarketCap 的网站
corn market cap API, get your API key now,
在 "coinmarketca.com/api/" 上点击 "GET YOUR API KEY NOW"
and we'll go ahead and sign up.
然后我们要先注册
Choose a basic plan. We'll agree and create my account,
选择 "Basic Plan"，选择 "agree" 并点击 "CREATE MY ACCOUNT"
we'll get an email verification. And we'll go ahead and verify.
我们会受到一封验证邮件，选择前往验证
Now in the coin market cap dashboard, we can copy our key.
现在，在 CoinMarketCap 的 "Dashboard" 界面，我们可以复制我们的密钥
And yep, you guessed it exactly what we're going to do with this key,
然后没错，你肯定猜到了，我们要怎么使用这个密钥
we're going to drop it into our dot env file,
我们要把这个密钥放到我们的 ".env" 文件中
or say coin market cap, API key equals and then paste it in there like that.
我们来写下 "COINMARKETCAP_API_KEY=" 然后把密钥粘贴过来
Now that we have our corn market cap API key in here,
现在我们有了这个 "COINMARKETCAP_API_KEY"
we can go back to our header dot config and add it in this corn market cap parameter.
就可以回到我们的 "hardhat.config" 里，并把它添加为 "coinmarketcap" 的参数
We're gonna do the exact same way we did above,
我们会使用和之前完全相同的方法
we'll do const, coin, market cap, API key equals process dot EMV, that coin market cap API key,
写下 "const COINMARKETCAP_API_KEY = process.env.COINMARKETCAP_API_KEY"
and then we'll take this sticking in here.
现在把它复制下来并粘贴到这里
So what this is going to do is actually going to make an API call to corn market cap,
它做的就是发起一个调用 CoinMarketCap 的 API 的请求
whenever we run our gas reporter.
就在我们每次运行 "gas reporter" 的时候
This is why sometimes you'll see me comment this out and uncomment it
这就是为什么你会看到我有时会注释掉它有时不会
because I don't always want it to make this API calls.
因为我并不总是想调用这个 API
But now what we can do now that it's enabled, we have an output file,
现在我们能做什么？它已经是 "enabled" 的了，我们还有了一个输出文件
we can see the currency and we have our API key,
我们可以查看货币并且拥有自己的 API 密钥
all we can do is run yarn hardhat test.
我们只需要运行 "yarn hardhat test"
And after all our tests pass, we're going to see a gas report.tx T
在我们所有的测试通过之后，我们将看到一个 "gas-report.txt" 文件
that we can go ahead and read from which has that gas report.
打开它看一下，里面就是 gas 报告
And now it actually has the USD price of each one of these transactions,
现在，它就包含了每笔交易的 USD 价格
it looks like at current prices, with Aetherium being $3,000 per eath,
看起来以当前的价格来算，每个以太币价值 3000 多美元
and a gas price of 43 Gwei, the store function would cost $6.
gas 价格是 43 gwei，"store" 函数将花费 6 美元
And the simple storage function would cost $64.
SimpleStorage 函数(口误：应为“合约部署”)将花费 64 美元
The current the Hardhead gas reporter actually comes with some different options, though,
目前的 "hardhat-gas-reporter" 实际上带有一些不同的选项
if you're going to be deploying to different network,
如果你想部署到不同的网络上
for example, with binance, Polygon, Avalanche or hecho.
例如 "Binance", "Polygon", "Avalanche" 或是 "Heco"
For example, let's say we wanted to deploy the polygon,
比方说，我们想部署到 Polygon 上
let's see how much deploying the polygon would cost
我们来看看部署到 Polygon 上需要花费多少
well in our WMV UHD ad token, Matic
来到我们的 ".env"(口误：应为 "hardhat.config.js") 添加 token: "MATIC"
And now we'd rerun this test.
现在我们要重新运行测试
And if we look at our gas report that takes T
如果我们查看 "gas-report.txt"
will now see the gas price of polygon right now is around 37 Gray per gas.
就能看到现在 Polygon 的 gas 价格大约是 37 gwei 每 gas
And the cost of Matic is 147 automatic and USD.
而 matic 的花费则是 1.47 USD 每 matic
Now we can see the cost of calling the simple storage method is going to be $0.00.
现在我们可以看到调用 "SimpleStorage" 的 "store" 方法会花费 0.00 美元
Now this of course is rounded down,
当然这是四舍五入的结果
but it's going to be really, really cheap to call store
不过这里调用 "store" 真的是非常非常便宜了
versus deploying the contract is going to cost three cents,
而部署合约则是花费 3 美分
I make it a habit to select false for my gas reporter
我习惯于把我的 "gasReporter" 选择为 false
whenever I don't want to actually work with the gas here.
只有我想处理 gas 的时候才打开
Awesome. Now sometimes when we're working with our code,
好的，现在当我们有时候处理代码时
if we don't have these environment variables specified
如果我们没有指定好这些环境变量
Hardhead might get a little bit upset with us.
Hardhat 就可能会比较“不爽”
So oftentimes, I'll add some code in here. So that these variables are always populated,
因此，我经常会在这里添加一些代码，以使这些变量始终处于被填充的状态
because we didn't specify our rink prpc URL, ring P RPC URL is going to be undefined.
因为如果我们没有指定 "Rinkeby RPC URL"，"RINKEBY_RPC_URL" 就会变成未定义状态
And that might throw some errors blow.
这就有可能导致下面出现报错
So oftentimes, what we'll do is I'll add an or parameter here, these double pipes mean or,
因此通常情况下，我会在这里添加一个“或”参数，这个双竖线 ("||") 就表示“或”
and in JavaScript, if we say some variable equals something or something else,
在 JavaScript 中，如果我们说某些变量等于某个东西或另一个东西时
what is really happening is we're gonna say,
实际上我们做的是
okay, rink, the RPC URL is going to be equal to process dot E and V dot rink, the RPC URL.
让 "RINKEBY_RPC_URL" 等于 "process.env.RINKEBY_RPC_URL"
But if this rink, the RPC URL doesn't exist,
但如果这个 "RINKEBY_RPC_URL" 并不存在
it's going to be whatever else is over here.
它就会是这里的任意其他内容
And I might write something like HTTPS eath Rinkeby. Example, or something like this,
我可能会写一些诸如 "https://eth-rinkeby/example" 之类的东西
just so that I don't make hard hat mad if I don't use rank B.
这样我就不会惹 Hardhat 不爽了，如果我不打算使用 Rinkeby 的话
And we can do something like that for all these.
我们可以对所有这些变量都这样做
So you'll see this syntax, oftentimes in a lot of code setups.
你经常会在很多代码设置中见到这种语法
Now the last thing that I'm going to show you
现在我要给你展示一下最后一件事
before going into the TypeScript edition of This is test coverage.
在进入这个脚本的 TypeScript 版本之前，要看一下 "test coverage"
And as we progressed to this course,
随着我们这个课程的进展
I'm going to show you more and more tools that you can use
我会向你展示越来越多的工具
to make sure that our simple storage contract is safe and secure.
以确保我们的 "SimpleStorage" 合约是安全可靠的
And we take all the steps we can to prevent any hacks from happening if we deploy in real life.
我们会尽可能采取一切措施以防止实际部署时遭到任何黑客攻击
One of those tools is a tool called solidity coverage.
其中之一就是这个名为 "solidity-coverage" 的工具
And this is also a hardhat plugin that we can use for our code.
这同样也是一个可以直接用于我们代码的 Hardhat 插件
solidity coverage is a project that goes through all of our tests
"solidity-coverage" 是这样一个项目，它通过遍历我们的测试
and sees exactly how many lines of code in our sample store dot Sol are actually covered.
以查看我们的 "SimpleStorage.sol" 有多少代码被测试所实际覆盖
And this can be a Good tip off.
这是一个很好的提示
If we don't cover some line of code, solidity coverage will say,
如果我们的某些代码没有被测试覆盖，"solidity-coverage" 就会告诉我们，
Hey, you don't have any tests for this line, maybe you should write some tests for it.
嘿，你没有为这一行编写任何测试，也许你应该写一下
We can add solidity coverage the same way we've been adding all of our packages.
我们可以添加一下 "solidity-coverage"，和我们添加其它包的方法完全一样
npm install dash, just save Dev, or since we're using yarn,
"npm install --save-dev"，或是我们要使用的 "yarn"
yarn, add dash dash Dev, solidity coverage.
"yarn add --dev solidity-coverage"
And we can then add this to our config,
然后我们就可以把它添加进我们的 "config" 中
the same way we've been adding everything to our config,
就和我们把其它包添加进 "config" 一样
go to our config, and we'll write require solidity coverage.
进入我们的 "config" 文件，写下 "require("solidity-coverage")"
And there's some configuration pieces we can add down here below for this,
我们还可以添加一些配置选项到这个下面
but we're just going to use the default
但我们只使用默认配置就行了
now we can do is run yarn, RT hat coverage.
现在我们就可以运行 "yarn hardhat coverage"
And this is going to go through our tests and print out a file that looks like this,
它会遍历我们的测试并打印一个看起来像这样的文件
we'll also get a file called coverage dot JSON,
我们同时会获取一个名为 "coverage.json" 的文件
which is basically this chart broken down a little bit more
它基本上就是这张图表的拆分形式
often put my coverage dot JSON in my dot get ignore.
通常我会把 "coverage.json" 放到我的 ".gitignore" 中
And I know we haven't actually seen dot Git ignore, do what it's supposed to do. But we will soon
我知道我们实际上还没有看到 ".gitignore" 文件发挥作用，但是很快就能看到
we can see here that about 50% of the code 50% of our statements in simple storage dot soul are covered.
我们可以看到 "SimpleStorage.sol" 中大约有 50% 的代码语句被覆盖
About two thirds of our functions are and 50% of the lines,
其中包含大约三分之二的函数和 50% 的代码行
It'll even give us exactly what lines aren't tested right now,
它甚至会告诉我们具体是哪些行还没有被测试
which we can see exactly 31 and 32 of simple swords, outsole aren't covered,
我们可以看到是 "SimpleStorage.sol" 的第 31 和 32 行还没有被覆盖
which makes a lot of sense, because 31 to 32 is this Add Person function,
说的很有道理，因为 31 和 32 行是这个 "addPersion" 函数
which we didn't call and we didn't add to our tests.
我们既没有调用它也没有把它添加进我们的测试中
If you want to take this time to pause
如果你打算花些时间暂停下来
and try to make this solidity coverage be 100% across the board, by writing some more tests,
并尝试通过编写更多的测试以使 "solidity-coverage" 的覆盖率达到 100%
I highly recommend you do so it'll be a great learning exercise.
那我强烈建议你试一试，这会是一个很好的学习练习
We'll also add the coverage folder.
我们要把 "coverage" 文件夹也添加进来
So covered adjacent and the coverage folder,
所以就是 "coverage.json" 以及 "coverage" 文件夹
which again, I'll explain what the dot get ignore folder does a little bit later.
再次说明一下，我稍后就会解释 ".gitignore" 文件的作用